Jye Chen TIAH | Mobile No.: 81823021 | Email: tiahjc@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/jye-chen-b272951a3

GitHub Profile: https://github.com/TiahJC



I am a passionate professional with a strong background in Full-Stack Developer, and have an unwavering desire to transition into the role of Solution Architect. My experience in ST Engineering allows me to have in touch with cloud engineering and took a strong liking to this profession. My job scope has equipped me with good understanding and deploying application into Kubernetes.

My technical proficiency, problem solving skills and adaptability makes me a strong candidate for this transition. I am committed to continue learning and professionally develop myself for this role.

EDUCATION

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Aug 2019 – May 2022

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical Electronic Engineering)Specialised in Info-Communication Engineering

Honours

Nanvang Polytechnic

Apr 2014 – May 2017

Diploma in Electrical Engineering with Eco-Design

- Diploma with Merit (Top 5%)
 - Director List in Multiple Semesters

ACADEMIC PROJECT

Nanyang Technology University, Singapore

May 2021 - May 2022

Final Year Project – Data Analytic for Energy Storage Safety

- Researched on Lithium Battery Remaining Useful Life
- Determined the best Al algorithm that suits for estimating State of Health and State of Charge parameters for calculating Remaining Useful Life of the Battery.
- Simulated the battery Model with Simulink.
- · Python programming was used to operate Machine Learning and Deep Learning Programs

Nanyang Polytechnic, Singapore

Oct 2016 - Jan 2017

Final Year Project - Design a program to detect obstacles around the Driverless Vehicle

- Developed a C++ Program by using Robotic Operating System (ROS) and Point Cloud Library (PCL) to obtain data type from laser sensor
- Optimised amount of memory used for the program for other purposes
- Validated by using driverless vehicle in NYP and run the program in campus compound

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Beng Hock Mechanical Engineering Pte. Ltd Electrical Engineering Internship

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- Implemented program for Self-Cleaning Toilet project using PLCNext Software.
- · Assisted deputy manager to improve SGBin Project.
- Redesigned electrical circuit and update implemented features using Electrical AutoCAD.

Singapore Technologies Engineering Ltd (Info-Comm System) Defense, Public Safety and Security Systems, Intern

Jan 2017 – Apr 2017

- Analysed problems with engineers from other companies to improve defense of Singapore Armed Force.
- Maintained and coded previous tracking systems to further eliminate errors and discomfort cause by the tracking system.
- Managed development of the Seletar Camp installation for People Access System and Vehicle Access System.
- Facilitated the teaching process on operation of system to users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Singapore Technologies Engineering Ltd (Mission Software Services) DataHub Integrations in Openshift Container Platform, Full Time

Jul 2022 – Current

Agile Methodology: Adopted Agile Scrum Methodolody, leading to improved project progression and

collaboration within the team.

- **API Gateway Implementation:** Successfully implemented a RestAPI gateway using WebMethods API Gateway Management, enhancing data security and accessibility.
- mTLS Implementation: Demonstrated a proficient understanding of mutual Transport Layer Security (mTLS) Encryption processes, ensuring data privacy and integrity. Documented clear graphical understanding to Project Team.
- **Prototyping and Simulation:** Utilized NodeJS skills to create a JSON file-based server to simulate use cases, allowing for comprehensive testing and refinement of data solutions.
- **OpenAPI and Swagger Implementation:** Designed and integrated OpenAPI and Swagger documentation for APIs. This included generation documentation, defining API contracts, and ensuring adherence to industry standards.
- **Solution Design and Deployment:** Developed Helm Charts and Manifests to facilitate the seamless deployment of applications within the OpenShift Container Platform, ensuring scalability and reliability.
- **Containerization:** Established a strong foundation in containerization (Dockerization), optimizing application delivery and management.
- CIS Benchmark Standards: I possess a clear and in-depth understanding of the CIS (Center for Internet Security) Benchmark standards for both Docker Container and Kubernetes. This knowledge includes comprehensive grasp of best practices, security guidelines, and compliance requirements outlined in the CIS Benchmark documents for these technologies.
- **Collaboration and Problem Solving:** Proactively engaged with Project Leader to address architecture and deployment challenges, providing well-researched, demonstrated solutions.
- **OWASP Top 10 Expertise:** I have a strong understanding of the OWASP Top 10, which represents the most critical web application security risks. This expertise allows me to architect and implement secure and resilient web applications, safeguarding them from prevalent security threats.

Singapore Technologies Engineering Ltd (Info-Comm System) Intelligent Transport and Mobility Systems, Contracted Staff

Jun 2017 – Aug 2017

- Coordinated with project team to bring national level project to completion
- · Analysed new configuration, plan and schedule updates for software version and data deployment
- Identified key problem areas and presented insights to supervisor for a smooth test ahead.

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

School of Engineering Club Executive Communities

Jan 2015 - May 2017

Freshman Orientation Human Resource In-Charge

- Analysed previous records and methods of promoting our events
- Outreached to undergraduates help an increase of 50% compared to previous years
- Entrusted to keep records of students' information by using Excel and RFID reader

SKILLS

Language: Proficient in English and Chinese

Skills Set:

- AutoCAD
- Electrical AutoCAD
- MATLAB
- C++
- C
- Python
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- PHP
- SQL
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Scikit Learn
- Tensor Flow

- PLC Ladder
- PLC Function Block
- HelmChart
- Bash Script
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Openshift
- TLS
- OWASP
- CIS Benchmark Docker
- CIS Benchmark Kubernetes
- Web Services (WebMethods)
- Postgresql
- MySQL
- ElasticSearch

- Networking and Network Policy
- Security
- DevOps
- Agile
- Scrum
- Documentation Skills
- Problem-Solving